William Parker Foulke Papers 1840-1865 Mss.B.F826
American Philosophical Society
- William Parker Foulke Papers, ca. 1840-1865; 3.75 linear feet (Box 1-7)
  - K
    - Kinley, Alexander M (Box 4)
    - Kirkbride, T. S. (Box 4)
    - Knox, John C (Box 4)
  - L (Box 4)
    - Lancaster County Prison (Box 4)
    - Landis, Henry D (Box 4)
    - Latrobe, John Hazlehurst Boneval (Box 4)
    - Law Academy of Philadelphia (Box 4)
    - Law Association (Box 4)
    - Law Cases (Box 4)
    - Law Certificate (Box 4)
    - Lea, Isaac (Box 4)
    - Lea, Nina (Box 4)
    - LeBrun, Napoleón Eugéne Henry Charles (Box 4)
    - LeConte, John L (Box 4)
    - Lecture on Induction (Box 4)
    - Lecture on Popular Studies (Box 4)
    - Lecture on Romance (Box 4)
    - Leesa, Isaac (Box 4)
    - Legal Briefs (Box 4)
    - Lehman, William (Box 4)
    - Leidy, Joseph (Box 4)
    - Lesley, J Peter (Box 4)
    - Lesley, J Peter Biographical Sketch of Foulke. (Box 4)
    - Lewis, J F (Box 4)
    - Lewis, Joseph (Box 4)
    - Library Company of Philadelphia (Box 4)
    - Lieber, Francis (Box 4)
    - Linding?, P C (Box 4)
    - List of Subscribers for Lands (Box 4)
    - Livingston, M (Box 4)
    - Lubbren, Frederick M (Box 4)
    - Ludlow, James R (Box 4)
    - Lykens, Isaac (Box 4)
    - Lynch, W[illiam?] F[rancis?] (Box 4)
    - Lytle, John J (Box 4)
  - M (Box 4)
    - McAllister and Co. (Box 4)
    - McCall, General (Box 4)
    - McCall, Mrs. George A (Box 4)
    - McIlvaine William (Box 4)
    - McLain, W. M. (Box 4)
    - McMichael, Morton (Box 4)
    - McMinn, W (Box 4)
    - McMurtrie, Francis (Box 4)
    - McPartland, Mary (Box 4)
    - McStround, George (Box 4)
    - Makanoy House (Box 4)
    - Malcolm, Henry (Box 4)
    - Mannor, Thomas B (Box 4)
    - Manwell, George Woods (Box 4)
    - Markland, John (Box 4)
    - Marriage Bond. Wm. and Julia Foulke (Box 4)
    - Marston, John (Box 4)
    - Martin, Balina (Box 4)
    - Maryland Penitentiary (Box 4)
    - Masonic Hall (Box 4)
    - Massachusetts State Prison (Box 4)
    - Matthew (Box 4)
    - Matthews, Adonisah (Box 4)
    - Memie, Charles (Box 4)
    - Memoranda., 1850 (Box 4)
    - Mendenhall, David (Box 4)
    - Miller, Anne H (Box 4)
    - Miller, Hugh (Box 4)
    - Miller, Spencer (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous Writings (Box 4)
    - Miscellany (Box 4)
    - Moravian Historical Society (Box 4)
    - Moreau-Christophe, L. M. (Box 4)
    - Morrele, L (Box 4)
    - Morrell, Edward (Box 4)
    - Morris, Ellwood (Box 4)
    - Morton, Samuel George (Box 4)
  - N (Box 4)
    - Nary, Joseph (Box 4)
    - National Democratic Quarterly Review (Box 4)
    - Neal, Joseph C (Box 4)
    - New York Prison Association (Box 4)
    - New York Prisons (Box 4)
    - Norman, Joseph (Box 4)
    - Notes on Albert Barnes' Essay (Box 4)
    - Notes on Discourse of General Harrison (Box 4)
  - O (Box 4)
    - Olden, Charles Smith (Box 4)
    - Olmsted, Edward (Box 4)
  - P
    - Packard, Frederick A (Box 5)
    - Packard, Frederick W Biographical Essay on Foulke. (Box 5)
    - Parker, Jeremiah (Box 5)
    - Parker, Richard (Box 5)
    - Parker, William (Box 5)
    - Parrish (Box 5)
    - Paulsons American Daily Advertiser (Box 5)
    - Pearce, J S (Box 5)
    - Peel Hall Estate (Box 5)
    - Pennsylvania Colonization Society (Box 5)
    - Pennsylvania Farm Journal (Box 5)
    - Pennsylvania Inquirer and National Gazette (Box 5)
    - Pennsylvania Literary Association (Box 5)
    - Pettel, William P (Box 5)
    - Philadelphia Association and Reading Room (Box 5)
    - Philadelphia Club (Box 5)
    - Philadelphia Holy Royal Arch Chapter (Box 5)
    - Philadelphia Prison Society (Box 5)
    - Philadelphia Society for Alleviating the Miseries of Public Prisons (Box 5)
    - Philadelphia Water Supply (Box 5)
    - Philadelphia Young Men's Society (Box 5)
    - Poems (Box 5)
    - Potter, A (Box 5)
    - Powel, H. W. Hare (Box 5)
    - Powel?, J (Box 5)
    - Powel, Katy (Box 5)
    - Powel, Mary (Box 5)
    - Powel, Robert H (Box 5)
    - Powel, Samuel (Box 5)
    - Preston Retrial (Box 5)
    - Price, Charles (Box 5)
    - Price, Elis K (Box 5)
    - Price, Jacob (Box 5)
    - Price, R Butler (Box 5)
    - Prison Committee (Box 5)
    - Prisons (Box 5)
    - Prissy (Box 5)
    - Prohibition Society (Box 5)
  - R (Box 5)
    - Rae, Dr. (Box 5)
    - Ravenel, Margaretta A (Box 5)
    - Read, Zach (Box 5)
    - Reed, William B (Box 5)
    - Rents (Box 5)
    - Rhey, John L (Box 5)
    - Rittenhouse, Joseph (Box 5)
    - Roberts, Soloman W (Box 5)
    - Rogers, Henry D (Box 5)
    - Rosengarten, G (Box 5)
    - Ruschenberger, W (Box 5)
    - Russ, John D[ennison?] (Box 5)
  - S (Box 5)
    - Sales, Sarah K (Box 5)
    - Schieffelin, H M (Box 5)
    - Setty, L Bransen (Box 5)
    - Select and Common Councils of Philadelphia (Box 5)
    - Settle, D S (Box 5)
    - Sharpless, Townsend (Box 5)
    - Sheafer, Peter W. Folder 1 (Box 5)
    - Sheafer, Peter W. Folder 2 (Box 5)
    - Shippen, W. (Box 5)
    - A. H. Simmons and Co. (Box 6)
    - Slack, J H (Box 6)
    - Smith, Charles E (Box 6)
    - Smith, George W (Box 6)
    - Smith, R H (Box 6)
    - Smith, William (Box 6)
    - Snyders, C A (Box 6)
    - Sparrow, Jeremiah (Box 6)
    - Spaughn, W H (Box 6)
    - Speech on Emigration (Box 6)
    - Streeter, T F (Box 6)
    - Stroebel, John C (Box 6)
    - Stroud, Eleanor H (Box 6)
    - Stroud, George M (Box 6)
    - Struther, I S (Box 6)
    - Sumner, Charles (Box 6)
  - T (Box 6)
    - Taylor, Richard (Box 6)
    - Tobrelet, I (Box 6)
    - Tower, C (Box 6)
    - Townsend, Edward (Box 6)
    - Townsend, Joseph B (Box 6)
    - Train, George Francis (Box 6)
    - Tyson, I R (Box 6)
  - V (Box 6)
    - Vaux, Richard (Box 6)
    - Vaux and Withers (Box 6)
    - Viele, Egbart L (Box 6)
    - Vondersmith, J V (Box 6)
  - W (Box 6)
    - Walker, John H (Box 6)
    - Wallace, J B (Box 6)
    - Wallace, John W (Box 6)
    - Ward, Townsend (Box 6)
    - Warder, George, et al. (Box 6)
    - Warder, John (Box 6)
    - Warner, D. B. (Box 6)
    - Warner, John (Box 6)
    - Warren, James C. (Box 6)
    - Watkins, M Carrington (Box 6)
    - Watson, John Fanning (Box 6)
    - Wheatley, Charles M (Box 6)
    - Wickersham, Cadwalader (Box 6)
    - Wilcocks, Alexander (Box 6)
    - Will of Wm. Parker (Box 6)
    - Williams, Daniel (Box 6)
    - Williams, Ennion (Box 6)
    - Williams, Henry I (Box 6)
    - "Willie" to Mother (Box 6)
    - Wilson, A P (Box 6)
    - [Wilson, John Wall]. Arctic Expedition Diary, Oct. 1853-Oct. 15, 1854; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Wisong, W A (Box 6)
    - Woodward, George W (Box 6)
    - Worrell, Isaac C (Box 6)
    - Fragments (Box 6)
    - Unknown (Box 6)
  - Photographs, These represent a sample of the available photographs in the William Parker Foulke Papers. (Box 7)
    - William Parker Foulke, full length portrait., n. d.; 1.0 Item(s); Full length view of Foulke, standing beside chair.
    - William Parker Foulke, bust, profile, formal., n. d.; 1.0 Item(s); Bust length profile of Foulke.
    - William Parker Foulke, half length, profile, formal, standing., 1.0 Item(s); Profile portrait of Foulke.
    - Lisa de Veaux Foulke., 1882; 1.0 Item(s); Full length view of Lisa de Veaux Foulke in evening gown.
    - Hallowell [?], bust, formal., n. d.; 1.0 Item(s); Frontal portrait of Hallowell [?].
    - Isaac Lea, bust, formal., n. d.; 1.0 Item(s); Formal 3/4 portrait of Lea wearing glasses.
  - Miscellaneous
    - Diaries, 1853,1854 (Box 7)
    - Diary. re. American Colonization Society, 1852 (Box 7)
    - Handwriting Copybooks (Box 7)
    - Maps
      Scope and Contents note
      Transferred to Map Room
    - Memorabilia (Box 7)
    - Newspaper Clippings (Box 7)
    - Notebooks Concerning Prisons and prisoners (Box 7)
    - Receipt Book (Box 7)
    - Account book, 1797; B F826.1; 1.0 vol. (Volume 1)
    - Commonplace book, 1843-45 (Box 7)